The wind is favorable, Your Majesty.
風勢對我們有利,陛下
If these fair winds continue, we will be able to arrive at
如果順風一直持續下去 我們再二到三天
Ketil's farm in two to three days.
就能抵達凱特爾的農場了
In any case... To think that the king himself is going to confront
但是,一想到國王要親自出馬
some wealthy family from the countryside...
收拾這些鄉間的富有人家
We, the Jomsvikings, would have been more than capable
交給我們約姆戰士就應該綽綽有餘
of taking care of it.
足以讓他們就範
King Canute has his own reasons,
庫奴特王自有他的盤算
Floki.
弗洛基
As a vassal, you should refrain from sticking your nose into such issues.
身為臣子 你該懂得“不在其位,不謀其政”
Jomsborg is an ally.
約姆戰士是聯盟關係
I don't exactly consider myself a vassal.
我不認為自己是任何人的臣子
Please don't forget that, Wulf.
請別忘了這一點,沃爾夫
Do you think Ketil and his men will resist
你們認為凱特爾和他的手下會抵抗
against their king?
他們的國王嗎?
I can't say for sure.
我不敢肯定
I heard that Ketil was so fierce that he was named Iron Fist on the battlefield.
我聽說凱特爾十分強悍 甚至在戰場上贏得了鐵拳這個封號
We can't let our guard down.
我們不能掉以輕心
He sure didn't seem that way.
他看起來不像是那種人
Humans are a valuable resource. I don't want to waste them.
人是寶貴的資產,我不希望浪費人才
If Ketil cowers before my power as king and surrenders,
如果凱特爾懾於我的王威主動投降
that would be best.
那是最好的了
Is that why you chose to confront them yourself?
這就是你決定要親自出馬的原因?
However, they are the ones who acted so shamelessly toward you, Your Majesty.
但是陛下,他們在你面前這麼無禮
Shouldn't we punish them
我們不該懲罰他們
and have them serve as a warning to the people?
拿他們殺雞儆猴嗎?
If they resist, I don't plan to go easy on them.
如果他們反抗的話 我也不打算對他們手下留情
"There's a tailwind.
“現在是順風
However, the waves are high
但是浪頭很高
and the land I seek is still far off."
我尋找的陸地仍在遠方”
Oh, I thought Master Ketil was back.
我以為是凱特爾主人回來了
But it was Thorgil.
但原來是托爾吉爾
Welcome back, Thorgil!
歡迎回來,托爾吉爾
Hey! Here's a souvenir for you. Catch!
給你們帶了紀念品,接好
Woah!
哇啊
What!
什麼?
A human?
一個人?
Woah! Master!
天啊,主人
Give him some alcohol and put him to bed.
給他喝點酒之後帶他上床睡覺
Jeez, he's such a handful.
天啊,他真是個麻煩
Hey, all of you!
喂,給我聽好
It's no time to be drying fish.
沒時間曬魚了
Get ready for war!
準備迎戰吧
Our enemy's army will be here soon.
敵人的大軍很快就要抵達了
They're coming to take over this entire farm.
他們要過來奪走整片農場
Gather all the men and weapons you can!
盡全力召集所有的壯丁和武器
- Hey... - What?
-嘿... -什麼?
Who is this "enemy"?
敵人是誰?
- How soon are they coming? - And what happened to the master?
-他們多快會抵達? -主人怎麼了?
- Hey, wait! - What is going on?
-等等 -這是怎麼回事?
Thorgil!
托爾吉爾
Before you start a war, you've got to honor your side of the deal.
在開戰之前 你得先履行你的諾言吧?
I don't want to be caught up in this.
我不想捲入這件事
Have that discussion with my dad.
這件事跟我爸說吧
I'm busy.
我很忙
Olmar! Hurry up!
歐瑪,動作快
This will be your first battle,
這會是你的首場戰役
so stay with me and learn how to fight.
跟在我身邊好好學習如何作戰
Although, considering our opponent,
但是,考量到我們的對手是誰
this may be your last battle.
這或許會是你最後一場戰役
Aren't you happy, Olmar?
你不開心嗎,歐瑪?
You've been wanting to fight in a war, right?
你一直想上戰場,對吧?
Get it together, Ketil.
振作起來,凱特爾
You said you would purchase our cargo at three times the standard price.
你說你會用高於市價 三倍的金額買下我們的貨
That's why we agreed to transport you guys all the way here.
所以我們才會同意 大老遠把你們載回來
Arnheid...
阿奴納...
What?
什麼?
Hey, Ketil!
凱特爾!
Wait a second, Ketil!
等等,凱特爾!
Come on, Ketil!
拜託你,凱特爾!
I'm sure it'll be all right.
我相信這一次會成功
Your gut is telling you, right?
你有強烈的預感,不是嗎?
This time, I'm sure it's the real Thorfinn.
我肯定這一次 一定就是真正的托爾芬
Yeah...
是吧
I'll hope for the best.
我會盡量往好處想
A war? Here?
會有戰爭?在這裡?
Within the next few days, apparently.
顯然就在幾天後
Thorgil said to fix the walls of the fort.
托爾吉爾要我們把堡壘的圍牆修好
Don't make it sound so easy.
別一副小事一樁的樣子
There's no way we can fix this in a few days.
我們絕不可能在幾天內就把圍牆修好
More like, who are we fighting?
但我們到底要跟誰打?
The thing is, he won't tell us.
他就是不肯告訴我們
He said he'll announce it when our army is ready.
他說等到整軍完畢時才會宣布
No matter who it is, we have no chance.
不管是誰,我們都別無選擇
There aren't enough
這座農場裡
people on this farm with experience in fighting a war.
有戰爭經驗的人手根本不夠
And we lost
而且我們還在前天
five precious warriors just the other day.
損失了五名珍貴的戰士
The guests
這些客人
seem agitated.
看來很激動
Maybe the master has returned.
或許是因為主人回來了
I wonder
不知道
what he will do
當他發現
when he finds out that Arnheid ran away.
阿奴納試圖逃走時,會有什麼反應?
Will he punish her?
他會懲罰她嗎?
It led to too many casualties.
這件事引起了很多傷亡
But
但是
the master adores Arnheid.
主人很疼愛阿奴納
He won't do anything too bad, right?
他不會做出太殘忍的事,對吧?
Yeah...
對...
Maybe not.
或許不會吧
She's carrying his child too, after all.
畢竟她懷了他的孩子
I'm so worried.
我好擔心
Do you think she's okay?
你覺得她會沒事嗎?
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Don't be.
不用說抱歉
You fought Snake and the others, right?
你對抗了蛇和其他人,不是嗎?
You did it for Arnheid and Gardar.
你為了阿奴納和哥達挺身而出
You even went against your oath for them.
為了他們 你甚至違背了自己立下的誓言
There are times when you just have to fight.
有時候你就是得出手反抗
Thank you, Thorfinn.
謝謝你,托爾芬
I like Snake.
我喜歡蛇
I think he's a kind and rational man.
我認為他是一個仁慈且理性的人
I didn't want to fight Snake.
我不想和蛇作對
And in the end, I let Gardar die.
而且到頭來,哥達還是喪命了
I'm not smart,
我不是個聰明人
so...
所以...
I can't explain it that well but...
我無法解釋得很清楚
I feel like there may have been a better way to go about it.
我覺得可能有更好的處理方式
Was it really necessary
真的有必要
to hurt so many people and end so many lives?
讓這麼多人受到傷害 犧牲這麼多人的性命嗎?
Did I even try to find an alternative route?
我到底有沒有試圖找尋過 另一種解決之道呢?
There was no way.
不可能的
So many guests were killed,
死了這麼多客人
so Snake couldn't back down.
蛇不可能視若無睹
Even still...
儘管如此...
violence should be
暴力應該是
the last resort.
最不得已的選擇
But...
但是
what would have been the best thing to do?
到底什麼才是最妥善的做法呢?
Where did all of this begin?
這一切是怎麼開始的?
I wish...
我希望...
I wish I knew how to choose the course of action that's best.
我希望我懂得選出最佳方案
Nobody in this world
這世上沒有任何人
deserves to be hurt.
應該受到傷害
You're right.
你說的對
You're exactly right.
說的完全正確
Arnheid?
阿奴納?
Where are you?
妳在哪裡?
Oh, what a surprise.
真是個驚喜
You returned so early.
你這麼快就回來了
I heard that King Harald passed away.
我聽說哈羅德國王過世了
Dear?
老公?
A... Arnheid?
阿奴納?
If you're looking for that shameless slave girl,
如果你在找那個不要臉的女奴隸
she was tied up and thrown into the stable.
她被五花大綁之後,丟在馬廄裡了
While you were gone, she caused quite the trouble, after all.
她在你出門的時候惹出了大麻煩
She plotted an escape.
她試圖逃跑
Forgetting about everything she owed to you.
完全忘了你對她付出的一切
"Escape"?
逃跑?
Arnheid?
阿奴納嗎?
A man from her past came around
她過去的相好出現了
and helped her.
幫了她一把
Many guests died.
死了很多客人
Two of our male slaves
我們的兩名男奴隸
helped her out as well.
也幫了她
What a wretched woman.
真是個卑鄙無恥的女人
This issue
這件事
must not be swept under the rug, dear.
你絕對不能善罷干休,老公
"Escape"?
逃跑?
Why...
為什麼?
Why is everything
為什麼一切...
slipping away from my hands?
都從我的指縫中溜走了?
"Escape," you say?
妳說“逃跑”?
Why?
為什麼?
I never heard anything about this.
我從沒聽說過這件事
I can't allow you in.
我不能讓你進來
It's true!
是真的
Ketil promised me that he will free Thorfinn.
凱特爾答應我他會放托爾芬自由
Anyway, I want to see his face at least.
總之,至少讓我見見他吧
I want to know if the Thorfinn who's here is the one I'm looking for.
我想知道這裡的這個托爾芬 是否就是我在尋找的那個人
I have to confirm with the master first.
我得先和主人確定一下
Otherwise, there is no way I am allowing
不然我絕不可能讓任何人
anyone to meet someone who is detained.
會見被扣押的人
All right, fine.
好吧,算了
Hey, come with me.
跟我來
Let's go find Ketil.
我們去找凱特爾
I'm sorry to bother you at such a busy time, Pater.
很抱歉 在這麼繁忙的時刻打擾你,帕特
No, I don't mind showing you the way...
不會,我不介意帶你過去...
Is there something wrong?
有什麼問題嗎?
I'm afraid this is something we can only ask
恐怕這種事我們也只能
an outsider like you.
對像你這樣的外來者開口
Excuse me, Leif,
不好意思,雷夫
but do you have a surplus in your budget for buying slaves?
你們有多餘的預算買奴隸嗎?
Well, a little.
有一些
After all, I was promised to get Thorfinn for free.
畢竟有人承諾我會放托爾芬自由
The master always keeps his promise.
主人總是說到做到
I'm sure Thorfinn and Einar will be no problem.
我肯定托爾芬和埃納爾 不會有什麼問題
But Arnheid would be difficult.
但阿奴納就比較困難了
I know I may be asking for too much,
我知道這或許是無理的要求
but Leif,
但是,雷夫
will you please buy
除了托爾芬之外
two more slaves in addition to Thorfinn?
可否請你再多買下兩名奴隸?
Arnheid...
阿奴納
Jeez, this is boring.
天啊,太無聊了
There's a woman in front of me and I can't even do anything to her.
我面前有個女人,但我絲毫動不得她
Stop acting all solemn.
別再裝模作樣了
You know, don't you?
妳很清楚,對吧?
The master is just going to
主人只會
spank you a few times and forgive you anyway.
賞妳幾個大板,然後就會原諒妳
He is just so soft when it comes to you.
只要與妳有關,他總是很心軟
You're lucky
妳真走運
your punishment wasn't left up to us guests.
不是由我們這些客人來懲罰妳
By now you would've been stripped naked
不然妳現在早就被扒光了衣服
and raped by us all like nobody's business.
被我們強暴到體無完膚
As a way to avenge our comrades who were killed.
這是為了替我們死去的兄弟復仇
Otherwise,
不然
our comrades won't be able to rest in peace.
我們的兄弟會死不瞑目
Don't you agree?
妳不同意嗎?
What are you doing?
你在做什麼?
Master!
主人
You are back?
你回來了?
Get out.
給我滾
I have business with Arnheid.
我跟阿奴納有事要談
Master, I was just... um...
主人,我只是...
Get out.
給我滾
You tried to run away from me?
妳試圖從我身邊逃跑?
Why, Arnheid?
為什麼,阿奴納?
Why?
為什麼?
Why don't you understand?
妳為什麼就是不懂?
What was it all for...?
這一切只是為了...
Do you look down on me?
你瞧不起我嗎?
I won't forgive anyone who robs me of my pride.
我不會饒過任何踐踏我尊嚴的人
Even if that someone
儘管那個人
is you,
是妳
Arnheid.
阿奴納
Stop...
住...手
Not my belly...
不要打我的肚子
There's a baby inside...
有個孩子在裡面
There is a baby inside my belly.
我肚子裡有個孩子
Please have mercy on me.
求你可憐可憐我
Whose child is it?
是誰的孩子?
I swear... I swear it is your child, Master.
我發誓...那是你的孩子,主人
It's true. Please believe me.
是真的,請相信我
"Believe"?
相信妳?
You were...
妳...
You were the only one I believed.
妳是我唯一信得過的人
Believe in what?
相信妳什麼?
What does it mean to believe?
相信個什麼東西?
"It's true"? "It's real"?
相信誰?相信什麼?
I didn't doubt it for a second.
我一秒都不曾懷疑過
And to lose it...
失去...
I will not allow it!
這種事我絕對不允許
I will make you pay, you thieves!
你們這些小偷,我要你們付出代價
I will punish you with my own hands!
我會親手懲罰你們
Arnheid!
阿奴納!
Considering the gravity of Arnheid's crime,
阿奴納的罪過確實不可饒恕
flogging is a valid punishment.
鞭刑是必須的懲罰
But if you keep hitting her, it will turn into a death penalty.
但如果你一直打個不停 就會變成死刑
Arnheid is your slave, Master.
阿奴納是你的奴隸,主人
You have the right to kill her.
你有權力殺了她
Are you okay with a death penalty?
你認為死了也無妨嗎?
If you're okay with that, I will let go of this stick.
如果是這樣的話,我會鬆開這根棍子
Treat her wounds, Pater.
帕特,幫她療傷
So scary...
好可怕
Ketil! If you don't want that slave girl anymore,
凱特爾,如果你不想要留下那名女奴
will you please sell her to me?
可以請你把她賣給我嗎?
I heard you had two more slaves other than Thorfinn
我聽說除了托爾芬之外 你還有兩名奴隸
and that both of them are his friends.
他們都是托爾芬的朋友
I will pay you money,
我會付錢給你
so please give them to me.
請你把他們賣給我
Who said I don't want her?
誰說我不想留下她?
As for Thorfinn and Einar,
至於托爾芬和埃納爾
you can take them wherever you want.
你想要把他們帶去哪裡都可以
But I won't sell Arnheid.
但我不會賣了阿奴納
That woman
那個女人
belongs to me.
是我的
She's alive.
她還活著
But she's still unconscious.
但她仍在昏迷當中
I don't know if she'll make it.
我不確定她能否撐下來
No, don't touch her, Einar.
不行,別碰她,埃納爾
She shouldn't be moved.
現在不該移動她
Unforgivable...
不可原諒...
Every single one of them is a thief.
他們每個人都是賊
Everything that I've nurtured...
我所孕育出的一切
Everything that I cherish...
我珍愛的一切
They're trying to steal it away.
他們試圖奪走這一切
Dad! Where were you?
爸,你跑哪去了?
There's a ton of things we need to do.
我們有一大堆事情要做
Also, I need armor...
還有,我需要盔甲
Hey, Dad!
爸!
Unforgivable... You thieves... I will punish you.
不可原諒...你們這群賊 我會好好懲罰你們
I don't care
即使你是國王
if you're the king.
我也不在乎
"The Battle of Ketil's Farm."
凱特爾農場之戰
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻譯:歐德慧